Ye Huang

+358 46 523 6667 sysuhuangye@gmail.com https://yehuang.me/

Profile

A big fan of web design and data visualisation, highly developed skills in Javascript, Python and Ruby, possessing specialist knowledge of Geoinformatics, 3 years of practical experience in web development ranging from responsive websites to HTML5 hybrid applications. To know more about me, please visit my personal website.

Experience

WEB DEVELOPER, SOLUE OY; HELSINKI, FINLAND - 2014-PRESENT

- ▶ Palkkaaminut.fi (11/2015 12/2015) <u>Palkkaaminut.fi</u> Front-end Developer Cooperating with designers to craft HTML mockups for <u>www.palkkaaminut.fi</u> based on Craft CMS, jQuery and Bootstrap.
- Fysios.fi (11/2015) <u>Fysios Group</u> Front-end Developer Participating the development of <u>Fysios official website</u> which was built on Craft CMS and integrated with Knockout.js and Foundation on the client-side.
- ▶ Witrafi Admin CMS (06/2015 12/2015) <u>Witrafi Oy</u> Front-end Developer Designing and Developing the client-side based on Witrafi's RESTful APIs, AngularJS and Bootstrap. Other tools for project management and testing included Yeoman, Grunt, Bower, Protractor and Jira.
- ▶ Grocialist (06/2015 11/2015) <u>Grocialist Oy</u> Front-end Developer Developing the client-side to make sure a complete integration with Grocialist's back-end. The main tech-stack was made up of AngularJS, Facebook APIs, jQuery and Bootstrap.
- AngularFire-Ionic Live Chat Room (02/2015 03/2015) Solue Oy Web Developer This project was a HTML5 hybrid mobile app for live chat and was originally designed to test the real-time feature of Firebase and the performance of Ionic on mobile platforms.
- Witrafi Cloud Parking Service (10/2014 08/2015) Witrafi Oy Front-end Developer Crafting a seamless client-server integration with AngularJS, Bootstrap, Witrafi's RESTful APIs, GoogleMap APIs and Solinor Payment APIs. Other tools contained Yeoman, Grunt, Jira and Slack.
- FinMeas HTML5 Hybrid Mobile App (09/2014 04/2015) FinMeas Oy Coordinator/Tester I was one of the project coordinators and my main duties were focused on proposing potential technical architectures, constructing mobile app mockups, managing the project and testing products before the final release. AngularJS and Sencha Touch were used for mockups. Other tools included Jira, Bitbucket and Slack.
- Aemdee Medical Online Service (05/2014 09/2014) Solue Oy Full-stack Developer Participating design and development of Aemdee web service as a full-stack developer by using Ruby on Rails, Backbone.js, jQuery, D3.js, CoffeeScript, Bootstrap and MySQL.

Diktamen/QuattroFolia/GloPos (05/2014 - 10/2015) - <u>Diktamen Oy/Quattro Folia Oy/GloPos</u> Technologies - QA Tester

Designing, documenting and implementing manual and functional test cases for Diktamen (A Healthcare App on Android, iOS and WP), QuattroFolia (A Healthcare App on Android) and GloPos (An Indoor Positioning App on Android), while reporting, tracking and managing bugs/features/improvements on Jira.

Logo & Business Card Design (07/2014 - 09/2014) - Solue Oy - Designer Re-designing a set of logos and business cards for Solue Oy by using Illustrator and Photoshop.

WEB DEVELOPER FREELANCER; HELSINKI, FINLAND - 2015

- ▶ Tapio Wirkkala and Rut Bryk Archive (08/2015 12/2015) <u>TWRB Foundation</u> Web Developer Crafting the technical solution and mockups, manipulating seed datasets by using FileMaker and building the <u>application</u> on top of AngularJS, Firebase and AWS S3/CloudFront CDN.
- AuroraXplorer (09/2015 11/2015) <u>AuroraXplorer Oy</u> Front-end Developer Developing the client-side of <u>AuroraXplorer</u> (a HTML5 mobile app) by using Ionic and AngularJS.
- DK Travel Online Service (04/2015 08/2015) DK Travel Web Developer Re-designing and implementing DK Travel's websites, including https://nordic.firebaseapp.com and https://nordicbus.firebaseapp.com (current website data is only for demonstration). The major tech-stack was made up of Firebase, AngularJS, GoogleMap APIs, Bootstrap and was managed under Yeoman, Grunt and Bower.

Education

- Aalto University, Finland Master's Degree in Geoinformatics, 2012-2016
- Sun Yat-sen University, China Bachelor's Degree in Geoinformatics, 2008-2012

Skills

- Programming languages and Databases: Javascript (AngularJS, ExtJS, Knockout.js, Backbone.js, D3.js, Sails), Python, Ruby (RoR), MongoDB, PostGIS, MySQL, FileMaker
- Development environments: Atom, Sublime Text, Vim, RubyMine, WebStorm, Grunt, Gulp, Git, Github, AWS, Bitbucket, Atlassian
- ▶ Visualisation tools: ArcGIS, OpenGeo, QGIS, Mapbox, CartoDB, Matlab, AI/PS

References

• Github, Linkedin, Personal Website

Address: Lintukorventie 2, FIN 02660 ESPOO

Fel: +358 46 523 6667

Email: sysuhuangye@gmail.com